Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Copper and Aluminum Mining Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning copper and aluminum mining companies operating in the North American West
1892-1958
Ndy33
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.46
(7 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning copper and aluminum mining companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, employee retirement plans, letters and notices to the stockholders, prospectuses, lists detailing the transfer of stock and cash, reports, deposit agreements, notices of redemption, statements, company descriptions and newsletters, informational pamphlets, profiles of company executives, reprints of newspaper articles, maps, employee retirement plans, subscription agreements, underwriting agreements, co-operative deposit agreements, balance sheets, trust agreements, mortgage indentures, and reorganization and readjustment plans and agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning copper and aluminum mining companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, employee retirement plans, letters and notices to the stockholders, prospectuses, lists detailing the transfer of stock and cash, reports, deposit agreements, notices of redemption, statements, company descriptions and newsletters, informational pamphlets, profiles of company executives, reprints of newspaper articles, maps, employee retirement plans, subscription agreements, underwriting agreements, co-operative deposit agreements, balance sheets, trust agreements, mortgage indentures, and reorganization and readjustment plans and agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged first by region, i.e. Canada and the United States, and then alphabetically by company name.
Copper mines and mining -- West (U.S.); Aluminum mines and mining -- West (U.S.); Mining corporations -- West (U.S.); Copper mines and mining -- Canada, Western; Aluminum mines and mining -- Canada, Western; Mining corporations -- Canada, Western; Financial statements -- Specimens.; British Columbia Copper Company, Limited; Canada Copper Corporation, Limited; Arizona Commercial Copper Company; Boston & Montana Consolidated Copper & Silver Mining Co; Boston and Montana Development Company; Butte Copper and Zinc Company; Callahan Zinc-Lead Company; Calumet & Arizona Mining Company; Chino Copper Company; Consolidated Coppermines Company; Consolidated Copper Mines Corporation; Davis-Daly Copper Company; Hecla Mining Company; Inspiration Copper Company; Inspiration Consolidated Copper Company; Kennecott Copper Corporation; Miami Copper Company; Nevada Consolidated Copper Company; New Idria Quicksilver Mining Company; North Butte Mining Company; Ohio Copper Company of Utah; Phelps Dodge Corporation; Ray Consolidated Copper Company; Ray Hercules Copper Company; Rex Consolidated Mining Company; Shattuck Arizona Copper Company; Tuolumne Copper Company; United Verde Extension Mining Company; Utah Copper Co; William H. Brown Collection
- British Columbia Copper Company, Limited, 1911-1914; Ndy33 C1 +B77; (4 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Canada Copper Corporation, Limited, 1917-1922; Ndy33 C1 +C16; (13 documents) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Montreal and Boston Consolidated Mining and Smelting Company, 1905; Ndy33 C1 +M76; (4 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Amalgamated Copper Company, 1899-1915; Ndy33 U2 +Am13; (4 documents) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Tin & Tungsten Company, 1918; Ndy33 U2 +Am35; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1921, 1922?; Ndy33 U2 +An13; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Arizona Commercial Copper Company, 1911; Ndy33 U2 +Ar46; (4 documents) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Boston and Montana Consolidated Copper and Silver Mining Company, 1899-1921; Ndy33 U2 +B65; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Boston and Montana Development Company, 1919-1922; Ndy33 U2 +B651; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Butte and Boston Mining Company, 1892-1896; Ndy33 U2 +B95; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Butte Central Copper Company, 1913; Ndy33 U2 +B965; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Butte Copper and Zinc Company, 1906?, 1915; Ndy33 U2 +B97; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Butte Coalition Mining Company, 1911-1912; Ndy33 U2 +B98; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Calaveras Copper Company, 1909, 1927; Ndy33 U2 +C125; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Callahan Zinc-Lead Company, 1916-1946; Ndy33 U2 +C132; (8 documents) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Calumet & Arizona Mining Company, 1911-1927; Ndy33 U2 +C136; (6 documents) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Chino Copper Company, 1909-1924; Ndy33 U2 +C44; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Consolidated Coppermines Company, 1913-1946; Ndy33 U2 +C764; (14 documents) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Consolidated Coppermines Corporation, 1922-1940; Ndy33 U2 +C7641; (31 documents) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Davis-Daly Copper Company, 1910-1924; Ndy33 U2 +D29; (7 documents) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Ely Central Copper Company of Delaware, 1906?-1911; Ndy33 U2 +EL9; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Hecla Mining Company, 1922-1955; Ndy33 U2 +H35; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Inspiration Copper Company, 1910-1912; Ndy33 U2 +In72; (2 documents) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Inspiration Consolidated Copper Company, 1912-1958; Ndy33 U2 +In76; (13 documents) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Kennecott Copper Corporation, 1915-1952; Ndy33 U2 +K35; (65 documents) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  Scope and Contents
  Included are documents from the Utah Copper Company.
- Magma Copper Company, 1922-1952; Ndy33 U2 +M27; (13 documents) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Mason Valley Mines Company, 1910-1922; Ndy33 U2 +M38; (4 documents) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Miami Copper Company, 1908-1922; Ndy33 U2 +M57; (9 documents) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Nevada Consolidated Copper Company, 1905-1933; Ndy33 U2 +N411; (13 documents) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Nevada-Utah Mines and Smelters Corporation, 1911-1912; Ndy33 U2 +N415; (19 documents) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- New Idria Quicksilver Mining Company, 1920-1923; Ndy33 U2 +N444; (12 documents) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Newhouse Mines and Smelters, 1909; Ndy33 U2 +N455; (2 documents) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Nixon-Nevada Copper Corporation, 1917-1927; Ndy33 U2 +N654; (4 documents) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- North Butte Mining Company, 1926-1931; Ndy33 U2 +N82; (12 documents) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- North Utah Mining Company, 1913; Ndy33 U2 +N83; (1 document) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Ohio and Arizona Copper Mining and Smelting Company, 1902; Ndy33 U2 +Oh29; (3 documents) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Ohio Copper Mining Company, 1914-1916; Ndy33 U2 +Oh3; (16 documents) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Ohio Copper Company of Utah, 1917-1923; Ndy33 U2 +Oh4; (5 documents) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Old Dominion Company, 1916; Ndy33 U2 +OL3; (1 document) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Phelps Dodge Corporation, 1939-1952; Ndy33 U2 +P52; (18 documents) (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
- Quicksilver Mining Company, 1915-1917; Ndy33 U2 +Q41; Includes a document in MS.; (3 documents) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Ray Central Copper Mining Company, 1911-1912; Ndy33 U2 +R211; (3 documents) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Ray Consolidated Copper Company, 1911-1924; Ndy33 U2 +R212; (12 documents) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Ray Hercules Copper Company, 1921-1922; Ndy33 U2 +R213; (11 documents) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Rex Consolidated Mining Company, 1917-1923; Ndy33 U2 +R32; (2 documents) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- St. Joseph Lead Company, 1918-1931; Ndy33 U2 +Sa2; (9 documents) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Shattuck Arizona Copper Company, 1915-1925; Ndy33 U2 +Sh2; (5 documents) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Texas Copper and Refining Company, 1918; Ndy33 U2 +T31; (2 documents) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Trinity Copper Company, 1930; Ndy33 U2 +T737; (8 documents) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Tuolumne Copper Company, 1924; Ndy33 U2 +T837; (1 document) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- United Verde Consolidated Copper Company, 1916; Ndy33 U2 +Un45; (1 document) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Included is an 11-page report giving a detailed description of the mine including maps of the area.
- United Verde Extension Mining Company, 1925-1940; Ndy33 U2 +Un46; (8 documents) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Utah Copper Company, 1908-1923; Ndy33 U2 +Ut21; (7 documents) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- West United Verde Copper Company, 1916-1918; Ndy33 U2 +W52; (4 documents) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Included is a detailed report of the mine property including maps, diagrams and reprinted newspaper articles.
- Western Union Mining Company, 1947; Ndy33 U2 +W524; (2 documents) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Western Utah Copper Company, 1912-1920; Ndy33 U2 +W525; (2 documents) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Zinc Concentrating Company, 1916; Ndy33 U2 +Z67; (1 document) (Box 6, Folder 11)